<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conoroneill.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Garmin Forerunner 955 Solar - A great watch with one infuriating design flaw</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/06/08/the-garmin-forerunner-955-solar-a-great-watch-with-one-infuriating-design-flaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/06/08/the-garmin-forerunner-955-solar-a-great-watch-with-one-infuriating-design-flaw/</guid>
      <description>After a couple of great years with the Forerunner 935, the ever-reducing battery life started to become annoying and I decided last summer to upgrade to the 955 Solar.
 Overall I like the feature-set and it generally feels like a solid upgrade to the 935. I particularly love the maps navigation. Being able to load up a course like the Beara Way Ultra and follow it via glances, along with some buzzes and beeps for major turns and going off-course, is an amazing time and hassle saver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inaugural Beara Way Ultra - Don&#39;t bring a knife to a gunfight</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/06/04/the-inaugural-beara-way-ultra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/06/04/the-inaugural-beara-way-ultra/</guid>
      <description>Guaranteed finish I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the great Hal Higdon&amp;rsquo;s training plan for an ultra would be:
 Do minimal daily sessions Do one long slow amble a week Skip core and glute exercises for a month Don&amp;rsquo;t get that long-term hamstring issue sorted out DNF after 88K of a different ultra three weeks prior Don&amp;rsquo;t sleep for the week beforehand  Setup for success like this, I headed to Castletownbere at 3am from Bandon to try the first ever Beara Way Ultra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brooks Caldera 6 is an ultra-devouring monster (but)</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/the-brooks-caldera-6-is-an-ultra-devouring-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/the-brooks-caldera-6-is-an-ultra-devouring-monster/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: See below for a major proviso to this post.
My entire history with Brooks until a few months ago was one pair of Adrenaline 19s which did not suit me at all. I always associated the brand with big reliable heavy running shoes for conservative joggers. The Caldera 6 takes that reputation and shreds it, in the best possible sense.
 The perfect shoe doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the hunt for the ultimate ultra-distance trail running shoe since I started going longer in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having a WTF moment at the Waterville Trail Running Festival</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/having-a-wtf-moment-at-the-waterville-trail-running-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/having-a-wtf-moment-at-the-waterville-trail-running-festival/</guid>
      <description>Waterville To my shame I had never been in Waterville until early 2022 when my Kerry Way Ultra recces began. Despite its remoteness, its position on the Ring of Kerry means it&amp;rsquo;s always busy and buzzing. And as an absolute bonus, all the tourist traffic means that vegans are very well catered for everywhere in the town!
Last year I also learned about the Waterville Trail Running Festival from Yvonne Walsh and vowed to give it a go this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Columbia OutDry Extreme Mesh is the running jacket I&#39;ve been dreaming of</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/02/13/columbia-outdry-extreme-mesh-running-jacket-ive-been-dreaming-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 05:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/02/13/columbia-outdry-extreme-mesh-running-jacket-ive-been-dreaming-of/</guid>
      <description>For someone who runs a lot in bad weather, I&amp;rsquo;ve bought very few running jackets since I started back in 2009. But once I started running trails, I had to up my game. They can be summarised as:
 2009-2017 Various cheap generic windcheaters 2017 - Decathlon heavy running jacket. Not very breathable. Still use it. 2018 - The classic Ronhill Infinity Torrent Running Jacket with the chest pocket square. Still great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conor&#39;s Top Tips for DNFing The Kerry Way Ultra</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2022/09/09/conors-top-tips-for-dnfing-the-kerry-way-ultra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2022/09/09/conors-top-tips-for-dnfing-the-kerry-way-ultra/</guid>
      <description>DNF? For non-runners reading this, DNF means Did Not Finish. In my preview post I ended with &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I do. Particularly when the rain comes in at night.&amp;rdquo;
On the plus side, the rain came in during daylight hours. But I&amp;rsquo;m getting ahead of myself. Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to the start.
Nope, nope, let&amp;rsquo;s thank some people first.
Thank Yous   Elieen - The woman, the legend. Words like &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;culture&amp;rdquo; have become overused and devalued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch your first Ultramarathon online with the Kerry Way Ultra</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2022/09/01/watch-your-first-ultramarathon-online-with-the-kerry-way-ultra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 06:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2022/09/01/watch-your-first-ultramarathon-online-with-the-kerry-way-ultra/</guid>
      <description>The Kerry Way Whilst millions of people have completed marathons over the past few decades, ultramarathons are still pretty niche. Ireland has a bunch of fantastic ultrarunners and a handful of amazing ultramarathons.
The big kahuna of them all is the Kerry Way Ultra, which is about to have its tenth outing on September 2nd and 3rd. The Kerry Way is a wonderful trail that traverses the entire Iveragh peninsula. Many people travel from the US and mainland Europe to do multi-day hikes of the route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirch Masala - Best vegan menu in Ireland?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>We are spending two weeks in Clon whilst our kitchen gets rebuilt and decided to treat ourselves to an Indian takeaway on the first night. A bit of googling revealed that there was a new place called Mirch Masala, so I loaded up their website on my phone and my jaw hit the floor as I started browsing the menu.
The range of vegan and vegetarian options is almost beyond belief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Flahavan&#39;s Oat Milk can out-market the big brands</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</guid>
      <description>I was so pleased when I heard Flahavan&amp;rsquo;s was getting into the oat milk market. As the most famous porridge brand in Ireland, it seemed like an obvious move.
 I only turned plant-based in January 2020 and switched to oat milk pretty quickly as I preferred, and still prefer, its taste to all the other plant milks. Having Flahavans as an option along with the usual Oatly, Califia, Minor Figures and Alpro means I can now finally support Irish farmers again with my cuppa tea and coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tre Cime di Lavaredo - A European wonder hiding in plain sight</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/15/tre-cime-di-lavaredo-a-european-wonder-hiding-in-plain-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/15/tre-cime-di-lavaredo-a-european-wonder-hiding-in-plain-sight/</guid>
      <description>I got those Pandemic City Blues Four weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of Tre Cime di Lavaredo. Last weekend we hiked around it and I&amp;rsquo;m still struggling to find the English to describe the beauty of what we saw. How we got there is kind of a funny story.
We humans have an ability to let trauma fade, which helps us in countless ways from childbirth and broken limbs to the death of loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kerry Way Ultra Lite 2021 - Beyond Words</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/03/the-kerry-way-ultra-lite-2021-beyond-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/03/the-kerry-way-ultra-lite-2021-beyond-words/</guid>
      <description>This post will not do The Kerry Way Ultra Lite justice but I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to decribe a wonderful race.
   &amp;nbsp;     Some Day I had been vaguely aware of the Kerry Way Ultra for quite a few years and I even heard an elite US ultra runner list it as their top bucket list race on a podcast. But it was so far out of reach for me as to be almost mythical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoka Speedgoat 4 - The perfect trail running shoe?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/22/hoka-speedgoat-4-the-perfect-trail-running-shoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/22/hoka-speedgoat-4-the-perfect-trail-running-shoe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having mixed success with trail runners in 2021 which you can read about in previous mini-reviews:
 Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX - Love the comfort and waterproofedness. Great for road-to-trail. Did 50-60 mile Sheeps&amp;rsquo;s Head Way twice in them. But very little grip in the wet. Saucony Peregrine 10 - Killed my heel. Unwearable. Great grip. Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max - Heavy, blister-inducing on rough ground, lethal on wet rocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty years of blogging on conoroneill.com</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/20/twenty-years-of-blogging-on-conoroneill-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/20/twenty-years-of-blogging-on-conoroneill-com/</guid>
      <description>I somehow missed the actual 20th Anniversary of the Blog back in April and finally noticed last week. This could be a massive post with links to highlights and lowlights over the past twenty years but I think I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to keep it short.
 After using Frontpage in the 90s and hosting a &amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo; on Indigo, Geocities and others, I made the move to Blogger on April 17th 2001. That was followed by the golden years of blogging from 2006-2010 on WordPress and eventually the move via various static site generators to Hugo a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Clive Sinclair R.I.P. - My Hero</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/17/sir-clive-sinclair-rip-my-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/17/sir-clive-sinclair-rip-my-hero/</guid>
      <description>Sir Clive Sinclair died on September 16th 2021 after a long illness. I knew this had been coming for quite a while based on internet rumblings but it&amp;rsquo;s still a shock to know that the man, whose brilliant mind changed the life of a small kid from rural Ireland, is gone.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve written many many many times over the years on this blog and on my tech blog about the ZX Spectrum and Sinclair in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-inov-8-trailfly-ultra-g-300-max/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-inov-8-trailfly-ultra-g-300-max/</guid>
      <description>After the heel-destroying catastrophe of the Saucony Peregrine 10 and my bad fall in the Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX, I needed a new pair of trail running shoes that could handle both long distance and typical slippy, mucky, wet Irish terrain.
The hype around the Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max has almost been as big as its crazy long name. But the reviews were very good and I still love and use my old Inov-8 X-CLAW 275 on the shorter boggier stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Saucony Peregrine 10 / 11</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-saucony-peregrine-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-saucony-peregrine-10-11/</guid>
      <description>This won&amp;rsquo;t be a long review. Whilst I was enjoying running in the Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX, I knew the grip wasn&amp;rsquo;t great on the rougher stuff. After googling around a bit, the Saucony Peregrine had lots of solid reviews as a reliable decent everyday trail running shoe. Version 10 was on discount due to the recent release of version 11, so I grabbed a pair from Alltricks in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sheep&#39;s Head Way Fastest Known Time (FKT)</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/the-sheeps-head-way-fkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/the-sheeps-head-way-fkt/</guid>
      <description>If at first On April 12th 2021 I attempted to do the entire main loop of The Sheep&amp;rsquo;s Head Way. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite make it but had an amazing day in a wonderful part of the world. Five weeks later on May 17th, I gave it another go. Whilst it didn&amp;rsquo;t go to plan, the outcome left me with a big old grin on my face for a week.
No you don&amp;rsquo;t need a gas cooker The two main problems I had the first time were my ridiculous pack full of everything from a gas cooker to a sleeping bag, along with the horrendous blisters on the soles of my feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sheep&#39;s Head (Way) - Ambling 51 miles in 21 hours</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/04/18/the-sheeps-head-way-ambling-51-miles-in-21-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/04/18/the-sheeps-head-way-ambling-51-miles-in-21-hours/</guid>
      <description>The Unlockdowning As we approached the partial lifting of pandemic lockdown in Ireland in late March 2021, I wanted to celebrate in some way that involved trails, hills and running. Luckily for me, the brilliant Tough Soles published a new summary video on YouTube of their Sheep&amp;rsquo;s Head Way hiking trip from 2018. I was immediately sold.
The route The official Way web-site has a ton of useful info including a trace of the whole route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using smashed phones as extra computers at home during the pandemic</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/03/12/using_smashed_phones_as_extra_computers_at_home_during_pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 10:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/03/12/using_smashed_phones_as_extra_computers_at_home_during_pandemic/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in maximising the lifetime of electronics. I detest built-in obsolescence and I hate the way computers are becoming impossible to upgrade or repair yourself. Apple is the absolute worst culprit in this area and their actions result in others following their terrible example.
Apple&amp;rsquo;s logic is that phones and computers should be like TVs and no-one ever upgrades or repairs their TV. Except, we used to. I still remember the RTV Rentals man coming to our house to replace the tuner in our TV as the existing one couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the signal of my new ZX Spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irish Lockdown Vegan Brown Soda Bread recipe</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 06:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</guid>
      <description>In January 2020, I went 99.9% plant-based as a way of kick-starting serious weight loss after 20 years of being either overweight or obese. The only initial exception was cow milk in my tea. I did similar back in 2016 but that was my silly &amp;ldquo;6 Day Vegan&amp;rdquo; plan where I ate chicken curry on a Friday. Both times I&amp;rsquo;ve used Veganuary as the starting point.
After two months at 99.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
