<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conoroneill.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mirch Masala - Best vegan menu in Ireland?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>We are spending two weeks in Clon whilst our kitchen gets rebuilt and decided to treat ourselves to an Indian takeaway on the first night. A bit of googling revealed that there was a new place called Mirch Masala, so I loaded up their website on my phone and my jaw hit the floor as I started browsing the menu.
The range of vegan and vegetarian options is almost beyond belief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Flahavan&#39;s Oat Milk can out-market the big brands</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</guid>
      <description>I was so pleased when I heard Flahavan&amp;rsquo;s was getting into the oat milk market. As the most famous porridge brand in Ireland, it seemed like an obvious move.
 I only turned plant-based in January 2020 and switched to oat milk pretty quickly as I preferred, and still prefer, its taste to all the other plant milks. Having Flahavans as an option along with the usual Oatly, Califia, Minor Figures and Alpro means I can now finally support Irish farmers again with my cuppa tea and coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tre Cime di Lavaredo - A European wonder hiding in plain sight</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/15/tre-cime-di-lavaredo-a-european-wonder-hiding-in-plain-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/15/tre-cime-di-lavaredo-a-european-wonder-hiding-in-plain-sight/</guid>
      <description>I got those Pandemic City Blues Four weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of Tre Cime di Lavaredo. Last weekend we hiked around it and I&amp;rsquo;m still struggling to find the English to describe the beauty of what we saw. How we got there is kind of a funny story.
We humans have an ability to let trauma fade, which helps us in countless ways from childbirth and broken limbs to the death of loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kerry Way Ultra Lite 2021 - Beyond Words</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/03/the-kerry-way-ultra-lite-2021-beyond-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/03/the-kerry-way-ultra-lite-2021-beyond-words/</guid>
      <description>This post will not do The Kerry Way Ultra Lite justice but I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to decribe a wonderful race.
   &amp;nbsp;     Some Day I had been vaguely aware of the Kerry Way Ultra for quite a few years and I even heard an elite US ultra runner list it as their top bucket list race on a podcast. But it was so far out of reach for me as to be almost mythical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoka Speedgoat 4 - The perfect trail running shoe?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/22/hoka-speedgoat-4-the-perfect-trail-running-shoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/22/hoka-speedgoat-4-the-perfect-trail-running-shoe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having mixed success with trail runners in 2021 which you can read about in previous mini-reviews:
 Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX - Love the comfort and waterproofedness. Great for road-to-trail. Did 50-60 mile Sheeps&amp;rsquo;s Head Way twice in them. But very little grip in the wet. Saucony Peregrine 10 - Killed my heel. Unwearable. Great grip. Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max - Heavy, blister-inducing on rough ground, lethal on wet rocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty years of blogging on conoroneill.com</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/20/twenty-years-of-blogging-on-conoroneill-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/20/twenty-years-of-blogging-on-conoroneill-com/</guid>
      <description>I somehow missed the actual 20th Anniversary of the Blog back in April and finally noticed last week. This could be a massive post with links to highlights and lowlights over the past twenty years but I think I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to keep it short.
 After using Frontpage in the 90s and hosting a &amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo; on Indigo, Geocities and others, I made the move to Blogger on April 17th 2001. That was followed by the golden years of blogging from 2006-2010 on WordPress and eventually the move via various static site generators to Hugo a few years back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Clive Sinclair R.I.P. - My Hero</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/17/sir-clive-sinclair-rip-my-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/09/17/sir-clive-sinclair-rip-my-hero/</guid>
      <description>Sir Clive Sinclair died on September 16th 2021 after a long illness. I knew this had been coming for quite a while based on internet rumblings but it&amp;rsquo;s still a shock to know that the man, whose brilliant mind changed the life of a small kid from rural Ireland, is gone.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve written many many many times over the years on this blog and on my tech blog about the ZX Spectrum and Sinclair in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-inov-8-trailfly-ultra-g-300-max/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-inov-8-trailfly-ultra-g-300-max/</guid>
      <description>After the heel-destroying catastrophe of the Saucony Peregrine 10 and my bad fall in the Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX, I needed a new pair of trail running shoes that could handle both long distance and typical slippy, mucky, wet Irish terrain.
The hype around the Inov-8 TrailFly Ultra G 300 Max has almost been as big as its crazy long name. But the reviews were very good and I still love and use my old Inov-8 X-CLAW 275 on the shorter boggier stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Saucony Peregrine 10 / 11</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-saucony-peregrine-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/review-of-saucony-peregrine-10-11/</guid>
      <description>This won&amp;rsquo;t be a long review. Whilst I was enjoying running in the Hoka Challenger ATR 5 GTX, I knew the grip wasn&amp;rsquo;t great on the rougher stuff. After googling around a bit, the Saucony Peregrine had lots of solid reviews as a reliable decent everyday trail running shoe. Version 10 was on discount due to the recent release of version 11, so I grabbed a pair from Alltricks in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sheep&#39;s Head Way Fastest Known Time (FKT)</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/the-sheeps-head-way-fkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/06/07/the-sheeps-head-way-fkt/</guid>
      <description>If at first On April 12th 2021 I attempted to do the entire main loop of The Sheep&amp;rsquo;s Head Way. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite make it but had an amazing day in a wonderful part of the world. Five weeks later on May 17th, I gave it another go. Whilst it didn&amp;rsquo;t go to plan, the outcome left me with a big old grin on my face for a week.
No you don&amp;rsquo;t need a gas cooker The two main problems I had the first time were my ridiculous pack full of everything from a gas cooker to a sleeping bag, along with the horrendous blisters on the soles of my feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sheep&#39;s Head (Way) - Ambling 51 miles in 21 hours</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/04/18/the-sheeps-head-way-ambling-51-miles-in-21-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/04/18/the-sheeps-head-way-ambling-51-miles-in-21-hours/</guid>
      <description>The Unlockdowning As we approached the partial lifting of pandemic lockdown in Ireland in late March 2021, I wanted to celebrate in some way that involved trails, hills and running. Luckily for me, the brilliant Tough Soles published a new summary video on YouTube of their Sheep&amp;rsquo;s Head Way hiking trip from 2018. I was immediately sold.
The route The official Way web-site has a ton of useful info including a trace of the whole route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using smashed phones as extra computers at home during the pandemic</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/03/12/using_smashed_phones_as_extra_computers_at_home_during_pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 10:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/03/12/using_smashed_phones_as_extra_computers_at_home_during_pandemic/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in maximising the lifetime of electronics. I detest built-in obsolescence and I hate the way computers are becoming impossible to upgrade or repair yourself. Apple is the absolute worst culprit in this area and their actions result in others following their terrible example.
Apple&amp;rsquo;s logic is that phones and computers should be like TVs and no-one ever upgrades or repairs their TV. Except, we used to. I still remember the RTV Rentals man coming to our house to replace the tuner in our TV as the existing one couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the signal of my new ZX Spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irish Lockdown Vegan Brown Soda Bread recipe</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 06:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</guid>
      <description>In January 2020, I went 99.9% plant-based as a way of kick-starting serious weight loss after 20 years of being either overweight or obese. The only initial exception was cow milk in my tea. I did similar back in 2016 but that was my silly &amp;ldquo;6 Day Vegan&amp;rdquo; plan where I ate chicken curry on a Friday. Both times I&amp;rsquo;ve used Veganuary as the starting point.
After two months at 99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Public</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2019/11/25/thinking-in-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2019/11/25/thinking-in-public/</guid>
      <description>Has it really been 13 months since I did a personal blogpost? So many things I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to share over the past year but never got around to. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to do my annual race/run wrap-up post over Christmas and I really want to get back into the regular blogging saddle since I&amp;rsquo;ve left Twitter and Facebook long behind.
And speaking of the two hellsites, this post by Sabrina Little on iRunFar is a perfect summary of how I have been feeling about online (and real-world) discourse over the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final words and stats on Flight EI123 and the death of the Aer Lingus brand</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/30/final-words-and-stats-on-flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/30/final-words-and-stats-on-flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been calling Twitter the Hate Machine and LinkedIn a Roach Motel for a long time. But they both really came up trumps with my EI123 blogpost.
 Unsurprisingly it turns out that IAG airlines have been treating passengers like garbage all over Europe and they are getting worse by the day. I received a large number of stories both publicly and privately that show a company which seems to detest the people who keep them in business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conor manages to get lost in the Galtees and only realises it later</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/22/conor-manages-to-get-lost-in-the-galtees-and-only-realises-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/22/conor-manages-to-get-lost-in-the-galtees-and-only-realises-later/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite sights in Ireland is when I&amp;rsquo;m driving south on the M8 motorway and the Galtee Mountains appear on the horizon. At certain times of the year and day, it&amp;rsquo;s breathtaking.
The 16yo and I had a fine time out there earlier in the year with Bandon Hillwalking Club on their Open Day but I wanted to find out how much of it was runnable by someone like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight EI123 and the death of the Aer Lingus brand</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/15/flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/15/flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</guid>
      <description>Buckle up, this is going to be the rantiest rant I&amp;rsquo;ve written in years. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about getting it off my chest as, based on our experiences over October 5th and 6th, it will have zero effect on the dire state of Aer Lingus.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do the timeline first and then dive into the death of once-well-regarded brand.
An early start but lots of excitement My wife, 5 kids and I woke at 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Honnold free solo 360 video - Mind-blowing in Google Cardboard</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/29/alex-honnold-free-solo-360-video-mind-blowing-in-google-cardboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/29/alex-honnold-free-solo-360-video-mind-blowing-in-google-cardboard/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Google Cardboard, you can still get some sense of the scale of what Alex Honnold achieved this year when he free soloed El Capitan in Yosemite if you use the 3D controls in YouTube.
Free Soloing is climbing without any equipment or safety ropes. What Alex did is one of the greatest sporting achievements by a human ever.
   I&amp;rsquo;ve no massive interest in climbing but after watching the Valley Uprising documentary last night (available to buy or watch or Netflix), I have a whole new appreciation for the mindset and philosophy of people like Honnold and John Bachar before him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mario Fraioli on Eliud Kipchoge&#39;s performance in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/18/mario-fraioli-on-eliud-kipchoges-performance-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/18/mario-fraioli-on-eliud-kipchoges-performance-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Mario nailed it, as always, in his weekly newsletter. You should subscribe.
&amp;ldquo;I understand the disbelief and the need to explain what many deemed impossible without some kind of assistance. But what if, at the end of the day, as Alex Hutchinson wrote for Outside, it was all Kipchoge? What if we were simply watching the greatest distance runner of all-time painting his masterpiece in real-time? What if we were witnessing the greatest feat of human endurance in history?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From NYC to Kerry, a wrap-up of my races over the past year</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/10/from-nyc-to-kerry-a-wrap-up-of-my-races-over-the-past-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 07:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/10/from-nyc-to-kerry-a-wrap-up-of-my-races-over-the-past-year/</guid>
      <description>Apart from a couple like the Liverpool to Manchester 50 miler, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been keeping up on my mini race reports over the past year. Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll find them useful if you&amp;rsquo;re planning for next year. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep them short and sweet.
New York City Marathon I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whey I never did a full race report on this because it was an incredible experience. It overtook London as the marathon that emotionally impacted me the most.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
